good morning everybody David Shapiro
here we are back for part two of the
um Knowledge Graph Supreme Court decision thing
so we're using chat GPT and gpt3 to help us along
and as a quick recap where we left off was um
I didn't get that far um but I downloaded about
22 Supreme Court opinions this was about
Anti-Trust law so a very specific domain
um and then I got them converted to text so that
is um I did that with another uh repo it's fine
but then what we did was the the big thing that we
achieved was that we figured out that we can get
gpt3 to just go ahead and write my um write the
uh Whatchamacallit for us the the knowledge graph
Json and so what I'm doing is the nodes that I
asked for was each node should be a case citation
precedent or prior opinion each node should
have several properties such as date case number
involved parties reasoning for including in this
opinion and other relevant information so that
um worked really well because you see like it's
got a case number it tells me when it happened
and then the reasoning so like involve parties
like great this is Phenom this is phenomenal
information so what we're doing is we're going
to create a cross-linked web as to like why
all these things are interlinked so that way
theoretically if a uh the the this hypothetical
use case if an attorney is researching antitrust
laws so that one they can you know go to a court
court of appeals or even present to the Supreme
Court they will have a masterful understanding
of established law and the reason that this is
important is because common law is um how law
Works in America it's by prior precedent is the
so you've got the the laws that are laid down by
the legislative branch and then interpreted by the
judicial branch and so the judicial branch keeps
track of their own interpretation right because
there's the legislative branches it it has to do
with separation of powers anyways so that's how
we got Where We Are um it worked really well and
um there's all kinds of what-ifs and gotchas that
I'm not going to worry about because this worked
really well and we can iterate over the over the
long term so but this I had to plug in manually
and it's about four pages so like if we do
if we search for how many new pages there are
one two three yeah one two three
so that this has four pages total
um which the that that was good so the
next problem is we got to take these and
regardless of how long they are we have to
break them down into chunks of four pages
maximum so rather than do this manually I was
like why don't I just ask chat GPT so here we go
um I have a folder named um uh let's see
um opinions uh text um this folder contains
um uh text files of scotus decisions um that
were converted from PDFs the pages are demarcated
by um by the words new page I need a python
function so I'm basically talking to this
thing like I'd be talking to a developer
I need the python function where I pass um
pass uh actually no I actually let's
just ask it to do the whole thing I
need a python function that um reads every
uh uh file in opinions underscore text um
and then breaks each file
into chunks of four pages um
the purpose of this is to um limit the size of
each subsequent file please then save the chunks
into um into a folder named chunks text
um and append um a serial number to
the original file name for instance um you know
star underscore one star underscore two and so on
all right let's see what it does
why would this violate the content policy
okay I sent in feedback um let's see
what we've got so import OS split text
files input folder output folder pages
per chunk so good it's parameterized it
um if not uh output folder make it nice
okay for file and Os Lister input folder
um with open OS path join input folder file r
as F read it excellent Pages equals split on
new page perfect so it understood that for I and
chunk enumerate page range zero pages per chunk
excellent so this is this is a list comprehension
that will break it into equal chunks or chunks
of four output file equals this underscore
plus oh dang that's good that's good okay
um this is wonderful so let's go to this
um I had started writing it and then I
was like I don't have the energy for this
I'm telling you I have said it on Twitter and
I've said it on mostly Twitter but LinkedIn
and a few other places English your ability
to describe what you want is going to be the
primary programming language from now on period
end of story if you can think through a function
then um yeah this is this is it so let's run
this let's see if this worked um need a command
prompt CD and we're in the scotus opinions um
and then we'll do python step 01 split chunks
why you no work um this actually happens
quite a bit let's see if it can fix it
um so thanks that mostly
worked but through this error
and you fixed that error please now if this
can debug this I know exactly what it is
yep yep there you go
you need to specify the encoding yep perfect
oh wow okay it's saying add the ignore flag
wonderful wonderful adding
encoding utf-8 should be sufficient
um so that goes to do
right here
hmm fascinating
did it get farther
this is weird though input folder
file contents read encoding utf-8
as infile so sometimes this happens um
let's see what is the encoding here so
sometimes what I do is I'll convert it
to something and then I'll convert back
so let's
yeah hmm
I wonder what happens if we do let's
add let's add that ignore thing rather
than rather than getting lost in the
weeds let's just do errors equal ignore
because you know what I looked at
the text file it looks fine to me
oh and let's also see if it um okay it got
pretty far already so it got pretty far in
the process before blowing up one two three
so now we've got all the chunks cool cool cool
um all right heck with it send it what do you mean
this was in
so this was in Split text files F right
oh it couldn't write it interesting
oh okay okay okay um so when we write it we
need to we need to convert it to ASCII and back
um so let's see if it understands this
oh man I'll be I'll be jazzed if
it if it understands this okay
um great that worked uh now I have
a new problem here's the error
um please find a solution for this new bug
so what so the problem here is and I
um yeah that you're trying to join a list of
strings that contain spaces I don't think so
new page nope that's not it
replace no no I don't think that's it I
think we need to fix the um string encoding
um here's the last part of the error
I feel like I'm talking to like Hal 9000.
yep there it is that's it
yep
ah so we need to add the encoding to
to utf-8 right okay that makes sense
this thing is smarter than me
um okay so when we write it yeah
oh that's the problem I okay
um encoding equals UTF eight okay cool
but uh this took way less brain power
okay let's see if that works DLS clear
screen that was fast all right so now
we have 144 chunks of text let's see what the
biggest one is 20 uh [Laughter] uh [Laughter]
I think the uh I think the
OCR messed up with this one
why do you believe that the Sherman Act
okay I'm probably disturbing my audience
what's funny is that it got the capital
letters fine but then the rest it's like
no I wonder if it was like if the scanner bed
was like moving too slowly or something foreign
I'm sorry okay I'm gonna pause this
because I'm gonna keep laughing
okay I had to stop and make myself tea
I'm still probably gonna be looking a
bit I'm sorry okay now normally oh sorry oh
I don't know why this is so funny normally
um this would uh what I would do is just
delete data but in this case I don't want to
lose anything and imagine like what if half of
our files were like this so let's come up with
a solution so I'm going to with so this this this
this function works so I'm going to say okay cool
let's make a new script so let's go back over to
Chad GPT great that all worked um but it turns
out the OCR barfed on a few files so the um so
there are lots of duplicated characters such as
um please write a new script using Spacey or
nltk to um de-duplicate uh extra characters
um search through all the files in um see
what was the folder name chunks.text in
chunks underscore text um deduplicate deduplicate
characters um and then save the cleaned up copy
um in a new folder called um dedupt text
all right
will that work
I don't know if that'll work is Spacey that good
or T and Doc
um okay I think I'll need to add the
encoding but let's give it a shot
and let me make sure I've
got Pippin pip install Spacey
okay so while that's running I will do
save and we'll come back here and we'll do
um Step oh two oh so you might notice I started
I I um I do my functions like in order so that
way like if you're looking at this repo you don't
have to like try and reverse engineer what order
to run things in like it's just intrinsic
documentation um dedupe characters dot pi
okay python step O2 and I know that it's going to
barf on this so let's do any coding E equals UTF
utf-9 utf-9 is clearly better than
utf-8 right it's the next mission
sorry I'm in a mood today apparently
you having a giggle Mite okay um
let's see if it works
I'm not going to use the GPU for
something this simple it's a small
skipping registered can't find and it
doesn't seem to be a python package huh
let's see um it gave me this error
what does it mean
it didn't work
and this is the value of
having good error messages kids
interesting all right
let's see if that worked still didn't work
um okay all right so in this case it seems like we
found a limitation still didn't work Spacey load
says requirement already satisfied
yeah it says it's already satisfied um
let's go let's go to Google
let's see if uh let's see if this
all right
import
so it looks like you need
to do you need to install
let's try this
that looks like it did a thing
sorry I wasn't talking through it so
basically I was looking I found I found
a Spacey issue on GitHub and um let's see it
hasn't bombed yet so I wonder if it's working
um dedupt cool there's nothing
that's 20 uh no it didn't work
still didn't work okay
um
yeah so seems like Spacey is not
sufficient or at least this isn't
um okay so let's go back here go back to this um
okay I got Spacey to load but the original script
does not work the words um in some files are
still wrong um with lots of duplicated characters
um so for instance
for example
I probably should ask another way
yep
yep okay so it's actually going to tell me
yeah use regex so that's regex is actually the
way I would have done it originally so it looks
like this might be the right way to do it it
so all right let's see what it says foreign
do the same thing okay
interesting
okay um let's give this a try I will give
that a try but what about uh words where
um there are supposed to be duplicated
characters like book or look
um does yours script handle that and we use nltk
or Spacey or something else
to account for correct words
also while this is running I'm going to address
the elephant in the room and that was it like a
week ago I made a video saying like meh chat GPT
isn't that great um and uh so obviously like I
kind of have my foot in my mouth because this
is amazing it also looks like it failed um so
all right let me do a time check we are at
23 minutes so we're almost done for the day
um oh there we go okay
all right uh it's yeah yeah it'll it's gonna
give me that thing so I think what we'll do is
we'll just check to see if this happens
because it's better to have some data than none
so uh I think what we'll do all right split
chunks that one worked dedupe characters so
what we need to do is find the ones where this
happened right so um generally it looks like
okay
looks like it only happened
in one document yeah okay so
in this case we'll say we'll pass in any file
that um starts with this so we'll we'll uh we'll
we'll eat the eat the cost and what I mean by
that is we'll just Excel accept that some data
is not going to be quite as good but that's
plausible because like it's an OCR mistake
but the thing is is we just need it to be small
enough to fit in um so de-duplicate characters uh
yeah I don't I don't think this is gonna work
so it it's close but it's not quite um
thanks um can you modify the uh the uh
the script that uses regex instead um the
only problem is in files with and the name
can you just sort um or filter
filter out any other files
okay so let's see what it comes up with there
meanwhile it looks like this is the largest
one that is um not good right so it's 13 000
characters long so let's see how many tokens
this is so as long as it's that's getting pretty
close um let's see if we can if if our uh prompt
will work so prompt
and then we'll do text DaVinci 03 temperature
zero and our maximum length is going to be
like 600 tokens otherwise it's going to be too
long so let's see if let's see if that's enough
the output is pretty short so
but Json is pretty token intensive so I
wouldn't be surprised if it yeah so we
ran out of space so it looks like we
need to go back and do smaller chunks
um but fortunately these earlier scripts
are really easy so for instance we just come
back here and instead of doing um uh we we just
update this so instead of four pages we do three
and so then what we'll do is we'll come in here
to opinions is fine chunks let's delete these
and then we'll rerun um python step 01 and
so now what we should have is more chunks
so now we have 188 chunks but you see the the um
that one that one
so this is this is now the largest and it's
only 10 kilobytes or nine nine thousand
um characters long so this should be small
enough to run let's see how many tokens it is
um okay so that's now we're down to
2800 tokens let me remove the Json part
so now we're at 2500 tokens
tops so we can do we can do
um we can do like 1450 so that's more than
twice as many tokens so let's see it's it's
more than twice as many tokens with uh 25 less
input so theoretically this should be the limit
um cool all right excellent I think this is good
all right so we're almost done for the
day um let's see what chat GPT said
do you duplicate characters yeah there we
go okay so let's do this for the D dupe
um so let's come back here save it and
then we'll do python step O2 dedupe
all right we needed to add the um
Whatchamacallit encoding encoding equals UTF eight
and then for the right and coding equals UTF eight
okay so now if we go to the dedupt oh
actually here we need to delete this
it did all of them interesting um
oh it that's no if if not in file
it got the logic wrong I'm like no it was
only supposed to do like five
of these let's try that again
there we go okay so now the largest
of these is eight kilobytes which is
plenty small so we come back to chunks and
we'll replace those replace yes so now our
absolute largest file is 10 kilobytes 9 300
characters so this should all easily fit within
um no this should all easily fit within our prompt
window here so now we need to just go ahead and um
run the thing so all right so let's say
excellent we are now ready to run our uh prompts
are you familiar with open AI python module
open AI is dot dot dot I'm wondering
if it's slowing down because
um uh people are waking up this is one advantage
of being a super early bird is I get up earlier
than like everyone else granted you know it's
always middle of the day somewhere in the world
um anyways uh so this may or may not help us with
um with this part so now let's see open file save
file open AI key text DaVinci 03 tempt that that
we can do this up to 1450 that's fine in code
all right so this I just cannibalized another um
thing um we do not want to clean that up because
this is going to be there that's fine all right
network error yeah I figured that would happen
um okay so let's do a refresh um I have
a folder called what is the name of my
folder God I have like chipmunk chip monk memory
it's hard chipmunk memory um called chunks.text
called chunks underscore text um
that is full of dot text files
um each file um please write a python
script that uses open AI module and
new module and calls um and uses text DaVinci
O3 as the engine we'll say as the model um
and uses the contents of the file
in the chunks folder to populate
a prompt The Prompt is stored as um let's
see prompt underscore Json LD uh citation
nodes dot text and has a placeholder called
um what did I call the placeholder chunk
called chunk um in other words
open the text file or no um let's
see open the prompt file then replace
chunk with the contents of the file from
chunks.text and use this as the prompt for
um openai set the temperature to zero and the
token count to 1450. let's see if that works
certainly here's a script that
should do what you have described
I do it differently because I use
Windows I know I'm a charlatan um
I think it's going to work because
so this is the the implications of this if
chat GPT knows how to call GPT in theory you
can create a machine that can do its
own experiments with language models
I want to say that again the implication here is
now we have a system of a machine that understands
the code to call itself well enough and then
obviously this thing is intelligent enough to
understand results you could in theory have
something that trains itself or makes its
own data sets or whatever um okay so I like this
whoops copy code let's come over here and do this
um I guess I didn't say what
to do with the response um
so we'll do let's see
um [Music] and then yeah we
don't need any of this stuff
so that's fine um and then we need to
rather than print um we'll need to save
great um the output from the the uh
let's see great now response dot text
should be in Json format can you
please save the output to a new folder
called um uh let's see we'll
say called AG underscore Json um
instead of just printing um we should
uh let's see otherwise uh say use the same file
name as the dot text file but just replace the dot
text with DOT Json um let's see before you write
this script can you uh tell me if you understand
um give me some pseudocode so I can check to make
sure we understand each other if this works yeah
well it understands the concept of pseudocode
and then it's going to go ahead and write the
script Okay cool so let's see if it fixes it
um asking for the pseudocode may or may not
be viable especially because this code is
so simple it might have been easier just to
ask for it to um to just go ahead and do it
um but yeah so we're also going to need to do
um in coding equals utf-8 always need to do that
here I'll just copy this
and then we'll need the same
yep okay
cool
so instead of printing it we save it
so with open as blah blah right so
let's go ahead and add grab this comma
um I think we're ready so then one last
thing though is um what I like to do is
we'll keep we'll keep the print um just that
way we know what's going on and uh we'll add
new line new line new line and then respond to
that text um here actually We'll add a little
little dmarc okay let's see if
this works CLS uh python step O3
open file is not defined ah right because I
used um my own function for that um so let me um
darn it here let me pause this for a
second I'll just copy this function
from somewhere else you don't need to see that
okay so what I had to do is I had to add this
function so what I usually do is because I have
a very particular way of doing things and I do it
every time I usually write my own open file and
um and write and save file function which always
does it in utf-8 which is why I have to keep
manually adding this stuff because you you pick a
default and you stick with it so rather than ASCII
or ANSI or whatever I just say everything
is utf-8 anyways this should work um CLS
and if this works I'll pause it we'll take a look
at the results and call it a day because then the
last step is going to be getting it all together
and visualizing it that is going to be fun
come on you can do it
um key error text
response dot text okay so it didn't like that
um all right well let me look
at one of my other functions
um let's see let's do YouTube generate
chapters so I do response choices text ah
response so it didn't understand that part
but that's fine um okay so instead we'll do
text equals and we'll do that
strip so then we'll just do text
and then right text so that should work
and away we go so 95 of this was done
with chat GPT if it works there was a
couple things that I had to fix manually um
but you know it did its best um and what I
was really impressed by one of the things
I was really impressed by oh there we go
um no such file it didn't like the backslash
backslash but we got we got some good Json here
um okay so then we got to open kg
Json replace dot text with blah okay
so let me tell it this say okay okay
that mostly worked uh but I got an error
um it may be important to note um
running on Windows here's the error
okay so it's going to be fixing this
so anyways there's just a couple things
um that it didn't like okay it didn't
wait is it that simple that it just it what
didn't exist oh it didn't create it okay
because the previous script it it
checked and then made sure it existed
um okay so anyways um yeah so there's only a
couple things that I had to go outside of this
or or background knowledge that I had but for
instance when I asked it to use Spacey or nltk
um it tried it didn't work but then it suggested
use regex instead which is you know I would have
done that as someone who's been cleaning up
uh bulk data for a long time um okay so then
it should add the little thing you
know it check if the yep there we
go this function this bit right here I'm
pointing at the screen you can't see it
um if it doesn't exist then make it okay cool
so basically all we need is this really you only
need to check once you don't need to check every
single time but whatever that's fine so then we'll
come down here check if it exists all right CLS
clear screen with any luck this worked but yeah
so most I mean the vast majority of the code it
did I just told it what to do now imagine you slap
a voice interface so then you don't even have to
um type it out right uh use whisper use open ai's
whisper hey are you listening open AI I want this
I want to be able to talk through the code um
okay so now we're saving this stuff it should
be here hey look at that okay so this will take
a little while to run but we've got good Json
it worked so I'm going to go ahead and stop the
video for today I'm gonna let this finish running
um and then tomorrow we will merge all this
together and visualize it thanks for watching